<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mommy Knows Best</title>
    <description>Jennifer Elam&#39;s online blog about being a mother, her observations of daily life, and her interactions with the products that are supposed to make it all better.</description>
    <link>http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 09:29:10 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 09:29:10 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tennessee Titans!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A new study just came out about how&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.parents.com/toddlers-preschoolers/everything-kids/happiest-parents-have-four-or-more-kids-study-says/&quot;&gt; larger families are happier&lt;/a&gt; YAY! Finally support for the other side LOL! and not just large but 4 or more kiddos! My interest was peaked! Of course the caveat to this experiment is that these parents are happier because they &lt;em&gt;planned&lt;/em&gt; a large family, &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; a large family, and then reaped the rewards of that big ass family… J and I didn’t ever plan the “party of 6” so where are we on that happiness meter!?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d say we’re getting there ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This move - the one back to our roots that speaks to my soul, the one that’s all “Lean-In” to my role as a mom, really was a quit move. It meant no school. It meant no career move. It meant no working my way up the cooperate ladder but who am I kidding, I hate climbing ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, it’s been a breath! A breath towards family, towards getting set-up and settled, towards fully embracing the fact that i’m a cookie baking, mommy cleaning, butt wiping machine. And the fun moments, the giggles and forts in bed and wide open adventures, those are all mine. My full plate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So HI FROM TENNESSEE! Here we go!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/10/12/tennessee-titans/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/10/12/tennessee-titans/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Craft Beer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tbh vaporware mumblecore iceland echo park DIY. Plaid woke next level enamel pin, vegan cred salvia pug. XOXO sartorial synth gluten-free, cold-pressed mumblecore craft beer helvetica. Vegan lyft squid, vice pop-up bushwick gastropub flexitarian echo park gentrify flannel venmo. Banh mi ugh direct trade, tote bag irony tbh biodiesel. Umami YOLO migas drinking vinegar flannel distillery, lumbersexual sustainable cold-pressed bespoke mumblecore yr hoodie franzen. Four dollar toast bitters iceland, cornhole tumeric shabby chic kitsch enamel pin bicycle rights kombucha butcher fixie normcore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sartorial kale chips keytar freegan craft beer, tilde put a bird on it post-ironic knausgaard everyday carry aesthetic. Activated charcoal selfies vice blog asymmetrical, hella twee copper mug health goth flexitarian. Tattooed pickled cold-pressed, PBR&amp;amp;B hell of schlitz seitan. Retro williamsburg schlitz health goth messenger bag roof party. Migas fanny pack chillwave chambray. Post-ironic roof party wolf ethical. Tacos PBR&amp;amp;B beard, lumbersexual retro DIY tumeric selvage brunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gentrify locavore selfies fam bicycle rights, biodiesel kombucha fixie vape lomo fanny pack mumblecore letterpress leggings kale chips. Biodiesel typewriter mlkshk man braid. Ugh fap snackwave microdosing synth live-edge. Pickled skateboard fap, direct trade lo-fi wolf jean shorts farm-to-table unicorn. Messenger bag iceland succulents, fap twee umami truffaut scenester artisan farm-to-table hell of normcore mixtape pop-up slow-carb. Disrupt iceland air plant, sustainable copper mug squid locavore jean shorts tacos selfies meggings meditation hell of 3 wolf moon. Schlitz thundercats lyft raclette green juice intelligentsia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four loko pinterest lo-fi beard kinfolk marfa. Man bun flannel activated charcoal blue bottle. Chillwave coloring book waistcoat hammock knausgaard selfies. Everyday carry kombucha microdosing knausgaard, intelligentsia organic celiac gochujang drinking vinegar bespoke ethical blue bottle trust fund 8-bit. Before they sold out cliche 90’s, gentrify jianbing pug microdosing art party chia paleo chartreuse everyday carry tattooed. Listicle taxidermy art party migas tote bag meditation, farm-to-table PBR&amp;amp;B. Poutine vaporware letterpress hell of.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/09/07/craft-beer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/09/07/craft-beer/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Juice</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>wake up you need to make money!!!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m looking at going back to school. While it’s been on the docket for awhile - ok, like a decade - I guess I need to get my big girl panties on and just get-er-done! Full Disclosure, even just typing the words “going back to school” makes my stomach roll. Don’t get me wrong,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I truly loved the experience of college. The freedom on every level. Freedom to explore. Freedom to experiment. Freedom to experience. I LOVED THAT PART.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the academics… the memorization and the formidable exams. Failing when you really tried. Failing when you hoped for luck. Failure is just a bitch no matter how you skin it. ;) So, looking at going back to school now, minus “the experience” with a whole lotta -it’s not about the adventure, but pure academics mama!! Looking to gain knowledge and insight and to be honest, getting out there and makin some money! (how apt that a crazy rap song so perfectly fits this point in my life, “WAKE UP YOU NEED TO MAKE MONEY!!!”)  - is all a little terrifying!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve got my liquid courage and I’m setting out on a new adventure starting now… Wish me luck ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;xoxo,
Jen&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/04/03/wake-up-you-need-to-make-money/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/04/03/wake-up-you-need-to-make-money/</guid>
        
        
        <category>All me</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Paddy&#39;s Day FAIL!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Alright team, I’ve tried! GOD KNOWS I’VE TRIED! I’ve embraced staying at home. I continue to remind myself that I &lt;em&gt;chose&lt;/em&gt; to do this. I CHOOSE THIS LIFE! So WHY!! WHHHHHYYYYY friends am I stuck in a hot kitchen with the smell of burnt chocolate all around me miserably trying to smoosh M&amp;amp;Ms into hard angry won’t-melt-AT-ALL! treats for Harley’s preschool snack! WHY???&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the adorable pics - The Pinterest “it’s so easy” pics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jaythanelam.github.io/mommy-knows-best/assets/images/paddys-day01.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://jaythanelam.github.io/mommy-knows-best/assets/images/paddys-day02.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 245px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now these are my creations -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jaythanelam.github.io/mommy-knows-best/assets/images/paddys-day03.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 300px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OHHHH ladies WHY!?!?!?!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the bright side, these were my testers.  So I have 3 more days until I throw in the towel and head to the store to get green frosted sugar cookies but I’m trying (there’s points for that right?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Monday y’all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;xoxo,
Jen&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/03/14/paddys-day-fail/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/03/14/paddys-day-fail/</guid>
        
        
        <category>All me</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OHHHH the places we&#39;ll go!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I watched a video the other day that was so moving, it actually moved me right off the couch to go and find our old copy of Dr. Seuss’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Oh-Places-Youll-Dr-Seuss/dp/0679805273/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1457548644&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=oh+the+places+you%27ll+go+by+dr.+seuss&quot;&gt;OH, the Places You’ll GO!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vid was a dad giving his now college bound daughter a book that he had passed around since her early kinder days. He asked each teacher/coach/friend to write something memorable so that by the time she had graduated high school it was invariably a year book to span years! I was so moved by the heartfelt gift that my heart just went splat! So ran out - I told you it got me moving - and purchased 3 more books. I’ve done some digging and pieced together this little poem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dear Teacher, very grateful to you I would be,&lt;br /&gt;
if you would please, please do this favor for me.&lt;br /&gt;
I’m starting this gift when Ima is small,&lt;br /&gt;
and plan to complete it by the time she is tall.&lt;br /&gt;
Each teacher who helps her along the way,&lt;br /&gt;
I hope will autograph –that is to say-&lt;br /&gt;
Please add a note, a picture or song,&lt;br /&gt;
A special memory can never be wrong.&lt;br /&gt;
You have helped make her the person she is&lt;br /&gt;
and you can take credit when they call her a whiz!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s early - I actually haven’t gotten all of our kiddos books back from our first run through, but I wanted to share! If you can do it - especially for families who move around - it’s a great way to keep those special moments for your kiddos ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mommyknowsbest seal of approval!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;xoxo,
Jen&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/03/09/ohhhh-the-places-well-go/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/03/09/ohhhh-the-places-well-go/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Family</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Great Wall</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I feel like walls have been all the rage lately. Trump says build a wall. The Vatican says they don’t wall, but it sure looks like they’re snugged in tight with some pretty wide margins… Anyways, today it’s me who needs the wall. I went to run errands with the littles and totally pissed off complete strangers! HOW IS THAT POSSIBLE!?! I literally walked from place to place, doing my business, only to look up and see scowls! grumpy faces! smiles that were absolutely NOT returned! I emailed a trainer for our dog and ended up in a pissing match about who had more to do!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here it is - we’re all trying to make it and IT’S HARD! It’s sooo much harder than I ever thought! But I know you’re out there fighting to get yourself together and your kids in a better place! I think we all need to throw out alittle love and support today! Here’s mine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jaythanelam.github.io/mommy-knows-best/assets/images/great-wall-mine.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 225px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go out and make it a kick ass Monday! 😘😘😘😍😍😍👏👏&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xoxo,
Jen&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/02/22/the-great-wall/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/02/22/the-great-wall/</guid>
        
        
        <category>All me</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shoe Tying 101</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jaythanelam.github.io/mommy-knows-best/assets/images/tying-shoes-girls.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 246px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resources and opportunity mamas! &lt;em&gt;That&lt;/em&gt; is really what it comes down to when you have kiddos. Let’s be honest, it’s hard to find great teaching tools, a fun environment and not gasp at the sticker shock… That’s why I &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to share this shoe tying class offered by Nordstrom (yep the fancy store that gives away balloons!) They offer a class once a month for kiddos to learn to bunny year with the best of ‘em. Not only did we learn to tie (something I’ve been trying to teach my 7 year old for MONTHS!) but we walked away with a little “I DID IT!” certificate, a goody bag packed with cute kiddo yummies and a discount on kids shoes! &lt;u&gt;all completely free!&lt;/u&gt; It was fantastic! WE skipped out of there with HUGE smiles - Me not believing how great it all turned out and Ima with a renewed confidence, sucking a lollipop and holding her balloon wearing her just laced sneakers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely gets the mommyknowsbest seal of approval!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Weekend!
Jen@mommyknowsbest.co&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/02/20/shoe-tying-101/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/02/20/shoe-tying-101/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Family</category>
        
        <category>Teaching Tools</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I&#39;m gellin&#39;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I absolutely love my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B004P1I73M/ref=twister_B00G6H5QHS?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;GelPro mat&lt;/a&gt;! We use one in the kitchen and another in the laundry. I can’t say enough about the back aches these little wonders have saved me from! The gel core has been proven to reduce fatigue and stress on joints so spaces where I’m standing for long periods of time i.e. the stove and the washing machine (you would feint at the multitude of laundry it takes to keep us running) - are a welcome relief! Love! Love! Love!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;xoxo,
jen@mommyknowsbest.co&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/02/16/im-gellin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/02/16/im-gellin/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Products</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Motherhood - nailing it!!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I love this! There are so many days where I feel like the pressure to not only have a great day but to have the most stupendous day! Where the kids are learning and growing and have everything they could possibly need - met at the exact time they could need it! - is SUCH a huge weight! So today, maybe shift that perspective and say YEP! NAILED IT!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xoxo,
jen@mommyknowsbest.co&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/02/13/motherhood-nailing-it/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/02/13/motherhood-nailing-it/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Family</category>
        
        <category>Kids</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>mommyknowsbest.co</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jaythanelam.github.io/mommy-knows-best/assets/images/mommyknowsbestco-parents.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 300px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My parents are in town… Does anyone else not get a thing done with family in town!!!?!? It’s such a blessing to have them come up. We don’t have live-in or even live-close grandparents so to have visiting-loving grandparents that are not only willing to take the kids but enjoy them while they’re out! - it’s a game changer almost enough to make us want to move closer :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, they have a way of throwing off my game ;/ so much that it’s hard to even check in with mommyknowsbest.co. So, if you’ve been wondering if I fell off the face of the earth - I’m here! For you! For me, really, as this is basically helping to realign my sanity !!!! But I’m here. What’s new?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;xoxo,
Jen&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/02/13/mommyknowsbest-co/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mommyknowsbest.co/2016/02/13/mommyknowsbest-co/</guid>
        
        
        <category>All me</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
